ATHENA REICH: In this clip, I'm going to talk about the Actors Union.
There's three ways you can be involved or not involved in the Union.
You could be a Union member, you can be an EMC member, or you can be Non-Union.
I'm a Union member so I have my Actors' Equity card.
This means that I can get into the Actors Union Lounge and then I can go early in the morning to an audition and I can sign up and I can actually get a time, a slot.
Now, if I'm in EMC, that's one step down from being in the Union, it means that I've done a certain number of weeks but not--less than 50 weeks of work in the theater.
And what that means is I have--I can get up there early and I get on an EMC list and after all the Equity people who've come have auditioned, then I need get to go.
So, a lot of times as EMC, it's pretty tough.
You gotta work really hard.
You go there, you show up and you might not get seen.
The last level is Non-Union.
You might get there.
You can wait a long time and you might not get seen but you can try.